## Carroll Vance

Address: 2210 West Dallas St #1142 Houston, Texas 77019

Email: <u>cs.vance@icloud.com</u> Phone: 832-991-0905

LinkedIn, Github & Portfolio: https://csvance.github.io

### **Profile**

I have professional experience working with embedded and real-time systems for a variety of applications including IoT and robotics. My current passion is machine learning, especially when it comes to computer vision and inference optimization. After working in the oil and gas services industry for seven years, I am currently pursuing higher education to develop a rigorous understanding of the theory and mathematics required to solve industry problems with machine learning.

### Skills

Trained, optimized, and deployed convolutional neural networks for object detection and classification on embedded systems. Proficient in Python and C/C++. Data cleaning and preprocessing at HPC scale with custom pipeline built with OpenMPI. Experience solving time series / sequence prediction problems with machine learning. Work with embedded Linux ranging from board bringup to custom distribution creation. Applied deep reinforcement learning techniques to solve problems in game theory.

## Education

**UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON – 2018-CURRENT - CGPA 3.83** 

Expected Graduation: Fall 2020 with B.S. in Computer Science & Minor in Mathematics

**HOUSTON COMMUNITY COLLEGE - 2016-2018 - CGPA 4.0** 

Studied Computer Science

# Experience

DATA SCIENCE INTERN, MEDICAL METRICS INC.; HOUSTON, TEXAS – 2019-CURRENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, WILDCAT DEVELOPMENT; SPRING, TEXAS – 2009-2016

Designed, implemented, and tested embedded software for companies such as Baker Hughes, Hewlett Packard Enterprise, and National Oilwell Varco

SYSTEMS VALIDATION TESTER, WAILUA TECHNOLOGY; HOUSTON, TEXAS – 2008-2009

Executed test plan for flash memory technology created by Spansion and Virident Systems

## Extracurricular

**IEEE UH - MAKERS CO-DIRECTOR 2019-CURRENT** 

Coordinating prototypes for demonstration at ECE Conferences involving companies and other institutions to showcase potential of students. Responsible for hosting Build-a-Bot, Makers' Arcade, and Makers' Showcase, as well as securing company sponsorship for events.

#### IEEE UH MAKERS – WORKSHOP COORDINATOR, 2018-2019

Coordinating educational workshops involving embedded systems, computer vision and machine learning. Working on group projects such as indoor autonomous drones and robotic arms. Community outreach events

DATA ANALYTICS IN STUDENT HANDS – MEMBER, 2018-CURRENT
PI MU EPSILON U.S. HONORARY NATIONAL MATHEMATICS SOCIETY– MEMBER, 2019-CURRENT

# **Projects**

### KERAS MOBILEDETECTNET

MobileDetectNet is an object detector which uses MobileNet feature extractor to predict bounding boxes. It was designed to be computationally efficient for deployment on embedded systems and easy to train with limited data. It was inspired by the simple yet effective design of DetectNet and enhanced with the anchor system from Faster R-CNN. It includes online data augmentation capabilities utilizing multiprocessing with generators.

Github: <a href="https://github.com/csvance/keras-mobile-detectnet">https://github.com/csvance/keras-mobile-detectnet</a>

### AIR POLLUTION TIME SERIES PREDICTION

Exploratory data analysis with 50GB dataset of pollution data in Texas ranging from 2000 to 2017. Created preprocessing pipeline using OpenMPI / multiprocessing to handle missing data, windowing, and sequence creation on an HPC cluster.

### JETSON TENSORRT

Created a series of ROS nodes for executing optimized deep learning object detection and classification inferences on nVidias' Jetson platform. 100% GPU preprocessing pipeline for minimal inference latency. Utilized ImageNet and OpenImages datasets to train object detector. Currently being used to develop a system to keep squirrels from taking fresh produce from gardens using blasts of water

Github: https://github.com/csvance/jetson\_tensorrt

#### **DEEP CONNECT FOUR**

Created a Deep Q Network that learned to play connect four purely by self play. Tuning reward levels and replay buffer to stabilize training and increase convergence speed.

Github: https://github.com/csvance/deep-connect-four

### ARM A7 BOARD BRINGUP

Conducted board bringup on a custom PCB based on NXP IMX6 reference design running embedded Linux. Changes to device tree to support custom hardware and sensors. Debugging many hardware and software issues. This resulted in patches to the kernel in the case of PCIe, cutting a trace that was grounding a clock signal for ethernet, and many other issues being addressed. Used kernel debugger along with logic analyzer to diagnose issues